1,500 miles of heroism and incredible adventure!
Cheyenne Autumn is a western film directed by John Ford.
A reluctant cavalry Captain must track a defiant tribe of migrating Cheyenne.
Capt. Thomas Archer, played by Richard Widmark.
Deborah Wright, played by Carroll Baker.
Capt. Wessels, played by Karl Malden.
Red Shirt, played by Sal Mineo.
Spanish woman, played by Dolores del Río.
Little Wolf, played by Ricardo Montalban.
Cheyenne Autumn is a 1964 American epic Western film starring Richard
Widmark, Carroll Baker, James Stewart, and Edward G.
It tells the story of a factual event, the Northern Cheyenne
Exodus of 1878–79, told with artistic license.
The film was the last Western directed by John Ford, who proclaimed it an
elegy for the Native Americans who had been abused by the U.S.
government and misrepresented in numerous of his own films.
With a budget of more than $4 million, the film was relatively unsuccessful at
the box office and failed to earn a profit for Warner Bros.
The film explores themes of oklahoma, native american, cavalry, cheyenne.